Come on!
Let's go!
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
There we go.
Slow down, slow down, slow down!
Okay, slow down.
ah i want to find the edge
Mike, Mike, Mike, look at there.
Mike, Mike, look at that.
Look at that.
You see that city out there, kid?
See that big town?
One day we're going to own that town, you and me.
What do you think of that?
Yeah.
This is my kid.
There has to be a crossroad, a place to draw the line.
And it comes down to the question, what is theirs and what is mine?
Hey, Uncle Pat, you better be careful.
You're going to throw that back out again.
Don't worry about me.
I can handle it.
Yeah?
So home from the wars, huh?
How you doing?
Oh, I'm doing fine.
Servicing all the widows in the neighborhood now.
Same old Uncle Pat.
Flat beer from rusty pipes.
If you only knew how I missed it.
You might have changed a lot, but they shouldn't have beat the wise guy out of you.
Not a chance of that.
I saved the apartment for you, sold it to a couple of yuppies.
They loved your mother's furniture.
They said it was quaint.
I still remember the day they came to repossess it.
Ah, well.
So what are you going to do now?
Make a million.
Well, in the meantime, I'll ask McDougal to give you a job while you're waiting.
No way.
It was good enough for your old man.
So was arthritis.
He supported a family, just like you're going to have to do.
No.
Not me.
I am not falling into that trap.
Every man wakes up one fine morning with the wife and kids.
Where'd they come from?
They weren't there last time I looked.
That's because most things in life, good and bad, just kind of happen to you.
Well, I'm going to make things happen for me.
Sure you will.
That'll be a buck for the beer.
What?
Your nephew comes home from serving his country, and he doesn't even rate a beer on the house?
Well, you don't get rich giving things away.
Oh, how do you get rich?
I'm going to give you your first lesson on the house.
I've been here 25 years, never bought a drink.
Right, Eddie?
Yeah.
I could testify to that.
In 1969, the Mets won the World Series.
Eddie here starts piling on the bar, demanding, uh, a round on the house.
Drinks for everybody, he says.
Tell him what I did, Eddie.
He whacked me with a club.
Almost knocked the eye out of my head.
That's your way of making money?
You outwork, outthink, outscheme, and outmaneuver.
You make no friends.
You trust nobody.
And you make damn sure you're the smartest guy in the room whenever the subject of money comes up.
I don't know, Uncle Pat.
Doesn't sound like too much fun to me.
Fun?
You want fun, you go play at the beach.
I think I'll try the city first.
Yeah, well, here.
This'll get you there in style.
Ooh.
$10.
Uncle Pat.
Why don't you buy Eddie a binge on me, huh?
Eddie, you gotta be quicker than that, man.
I've always wanted to work on Wall Street.
I read the journal.
I know what's going on today.
And I'm willing to do whatever it takes to succeed.
I appreciate that, Flanagan, but all our professionals have college degrees.
I catch on pretty quick.
You're wasting your time.
Just forget the street.
No.
We're not interested.
A guy like you, advertising.
I have a feel for advertising.
I mean, I can look at an ad and tell you what's wrong with it.
Mr. Flanagan, we need solid credentials.
No, a marketing degree is a prerequisite.
Try the networks.
In the Army, I spend a lot of time in communications.
I think I can help you.
Well, we need somebody who can hit the ground running.
Sorry.
Maybe in six or eight months, but... You should pursue other avenues.
Try something else.
Maybe you could reenlist.
I believe in positive thinking.
Never quit.
Never say die.
I want to be part of the team.
So, what do you think?
Your resume's completely inadequate.
I'm willing to start at the bottom.
You're aiming too high.
I'll do anything.
You don't have enough experience.
No, I need a job.
We value education.
We require a degree.
You should go to college.
Bar's closed, pal.
I know, I'm looking for the manager.
What's the matter?
Find a hair in your quiche?
No, I'm looking for a job.
I see.
You want to put a hair in somebody else's quiche.
Just get canned?
I'm looking.
Looking for something better.
Coughlin's law.
Anything else is always something better.
Coughlin's law?
Douglas Coughlin.
Logical negativist.
Flourished in the last part of the 20th century.
Propounded a set of laws that the world generally ignored.
To its detriment.
Me.
Ever work behind the bar?
My uncle's in the business.
Do you know how to make a red-eye, Mr... what's your name?
Brian Flanagan.
No, I'm sorry.
I haven't had the pleasure as yet.
What about a vodka martini with a perno float?
I'm a fast learner.
Throw a 400-pound psychopath out of a bar?
Guess I could if I had to.
What about a 100-pound ballerina that's been speeding for three days?
Just open the door and let her pirouette out in the street?
These are just some of the tasks you'll be asked to perform, young Flanagan.
This is the Upper East Side, the saloon capital of the world.
Big time.
Are you ready for the big time young Mr. Flanagan?
I think I can handle it.
Get your act together.
Hey, come on, man.
I've got four people waiting for me.
I'm not even going back there with three drinks.
I know, it's coming.
With a twist, an absolute on the rocks, skilfies and tonic, and a velvet hammer.
This isn't what I ordered.
What was that?
A bosun and a cubaliva.
Oh, I ordered.
Woo!
Ugh!
If you're gonna sit in the water, go to Coney Island!
You want me to bite the top off this?
Yeah.
This is a good recipe.
Ordering a Cuba Libra.
Could I please have a glass of water?
She doesn't know how to make it.
Where's my Jim Beam on the rock?
It's coming.
I'm not leaving till I get my Cuba Libra.
Excuse me.
Can I have an order, Nelson?
This isn't what I ordered.
Ordering a white card.
You bitch!
Why didn't you just tell me it was a rum and coke?
Could I have what I ordered?
An angel tip.
A white wine.
Pink squirrel.
A fire top.
A sing-a-ling.
A white wine.
Pink squirrel.
Angel tip.
Dirty mother.
Could I have what I ordered?
All right.
Now, what was it that you ordered?
A martini.
What's in that?
Supposed to get 10% from the waitresses.
I don't deserve it.
You schmuck.
You get money from girls every day?
Listen, I'm sorry I called you a bitch.
Why?
I am a bitch.
Got yourself a new disciple?
Good night, my beautiful.
Hey, frog man.
Anyone that can get money out of her is a major talent.
Come back next Thursday.
I've got five shifts open.
You're offering me a job?
Uh-huh.
The waitresses hate me.
Well, you wait till you've given them crabs.
Then you'll really know hatred.
Today, I'd like to continue our discussion of the demand for money by focusing on the money multiplier.
We've got to add increases in currency, deposits, reserves, and bank credit along the whole system.
Then what we have is the sum of an infinite series.
Adding together the increases in currency and deposits, we find that they add up to 1 plus Cu over Cu plus Re.
That simply stated is the money multiplier.
Now, moving on.
The essential technique of bartending.
The less you pour, the more you score.
The boss does better, we do better.
And the customer?
Think of the customer as a hurdler thinks of a hurdle, a means to an end.
We dazzle him with ice work, we baffle him with bottle work.
There are many ways to fool a customer.
The short pour.
The long pour.
The ice mountain, the spring thaw, the speed rack shuffle, the hot shot.
You will learn them all.
Yes, Obi-Wan.
Both hands, ladies, ladies, come on, come on.
Okay, ready?
One, two, three, let's go!
Yeah, what does it mean?
What does it mean?
Nothing!
Nothing?
Hey, nothing?
Whoa!
Very sophisticated, man.
Good job.
You got talent.
Come on, let's go with a drink.
We're making money tonight.
Let's make some money for a drink.
Yeah.
Ice.
Thank you!
I guess that's what you learn in college, right?
Pretty fun, see?
Don't forget my beer, Sprite!
Missed me.
Hang on!
See, the name of the game is woman.
Little darlings come in a-panting, their little hearts a-pitter-patting for the handsome, all-knowing bartender.
And in their wake, a parade of slobbering geeks with one hand on their crutches and the other hand on their wallets.
You get the women, you get the bucks, and boy, oh, boy, you've got them.
Buttons were popping, skirts were rising.
When you can see the color of their panties, then you know you've got talent.
Stick with me, son, I'll make you a star.
Thanks, man, but I gotta be honest.
This is just a part-time gig for me.
I'm in a business program, City College days.
Ah, seeker of wisdom and truth.
You couldn't have found a better work-study program than right here.
To a future leader of America.
I'll stick with the brew.
Beer is for breakfast round here.
Drink or be gone.
I realize I've got a class of budding capitalists here that most of you are seeking the fast track, lovely term, to a career in investment banking or some other socially useful pursuit.
Nevertheless, certain antiquated skills such as reading and writing remain a part of the curriculum.
So, for your first assignment,
I'd like you to write your own obituaries.
Not that I wish you were dead.
At least, not yet, anyway.
Brian Flanagan, Senator Brian Flanagan, billionaire governor Brian Flanagan, whose self-propelled meteoric rise to wealth and fame would have made even J.D.
Rockefeller envious, died early yesterday morning at the age of 99 while bedding his 18-year-old seventh wife,
who is recovering from exhaustion at the local hospital and will be unable to attend the funeral.
For your midterm paper, I want you to select a business in which you are interested and to prepare a complete plan for its development.
You should include capitalization, administrative costs, income prospectus,
Marketing.
Cost analysis.
Blue shirt, fifth row.
Wake up!
Ah, light dawns on Marblehead.
Where was I?
Oh, yeah!
You're gonna have to face it You're addicted to love Might as well face it You're addicted to love
Might as well face it, you're addicted to love!
I have got serious fuck-me-eyes coming over here.
Stay in formation, our old man's coming in right behind us.
Time, time.
I'm doing the best I can, okay?
Sexual frustration.
I asked you to prepare a business plan, a seemingly simple assignment, and yet one word describes your papers.
Bankrupt!
A word some of you will get to know well in the future.
Like Mr. Ron LeMaster.
Where is Ronnie LeMaster?
Yes, our cosmetics magnate who hopes to make his fortune selling makeup for pets.
Fetch, Ronnie, fetch.
Good boy.
And my own personal favorite, Mrs. Sheila Rivkin.
Oh, my God, he's got my paper.
Mrs. Ripken has spent the last 20 years burning her husband's dinners, but now decides she wants to become the Donald Trump of the cookie business.
You.
You have something to contribute?
I just said it wasn't worth getting upset about.
What's your name?
Brian Flanagan.
Now speak up.
Let the class hear you.
Brian Flanagan.
Oh, yes.
Flanagan.
Mr. Flanagan.
Mr. Brian Flanagan.
Yes, Mr. Flanagan is determined to revolutionize the bar business by franchising his version of the local New York tavern to every suburban shopping mall in America.
Tell me, Mr. Flanagan, do you intend to provide the smell of stale beer?
Or perhaps a surly bartender and three boring drunks to each outlet?
I don't know.
Are you looking for another job?
Ah, diamond in the rough.
The dreamer who can't take the criticism.
Not from a guy who hides here because he can't hack it in the real world.
Okay, Flanagan.
Let's see how well you hack it in the real world with an F in this course.
F!
You're not a goddamn thing any one of those professors says makes a difference on the street.
If you know that, you're ready to graduate.
Maybe I'm just too old to be a student.
Oh, Christ.
I've got to find something, something to do.
Relax.
You're in the perfect job.
There's no better way to make it than behind three feet of mahogany.
Within one square mile of this saloon lies the greatest concentration of wealth in the world.
Yes.
But how was a bartender?
Can he get his hands on any of it?
A bartender is the aristocrat of the working class.
He can make all kinds of moves if he's smart.
There are investors out there.
There are angels.
There are suckers.
There are rich women with nothing to do with their money.
You can stand in this bar and you can be struck by lightning.
I've seen it happen.
Shall I continue?
Oh, please do.
Chantilly lace, and a pretty face, and a ponytail, just a hanging down, a wiggle, and a walk, and a giggle, and a talk, makes the world go round and round like a big-eyed girl, and make me act so funny, make me spend my money, make me feel good, like a real goose.
Oh, baby, that's what I like.
It is not dignified to get this drunk.
You are in training.
I'm in training.
For stardom.
I don't care how liberated this world becomes.
A man will always be judged on the amount of alcohol he can consume.
Always.
And a woman will be impressed whether she likes it or not.
Now, come on.
I'm not gonna make it.
You are.
A star never pukes or passes out in public.
Ah!
Holy shit.
Hey, are you okay?
You alive?
However, falling downstairs is allowed.
Whoops!
You sure you don't want a slice?
For breakfast, you've got to be joking.
It's better than a red-eye.
Look for a hangover.
Coughlin's diet.
Cocktails and dreams.
Hey, that's not a bad name for a joint.
You know, we really ought to think about setting up our own place.
That takes money.
The kind of money your sacred books dangle but never deliver.
They deliver.
You just got to know how to read.
Come on, we could make a fortune.
I mean, that's why you came to New York.
That's sure as hell why I left Queens.
Positive.
Positive thinking.
You can't let a little thing like cash stand in our way.
Cocktails and dreams.
I see it in pink neon.
Blink, blink, pinkity-blink.
That is a little corny, isn't it?
But I could live with it.
Yes, but can I live with young Flanagan?
Well, maybe I could handle a partner.
All right.
50-50.
A partner who knows his place.
70-30.
Well, you do have your pension to think about, so I will settle for 60-40.
To health and friendship.
Life and love.
Our future.
To our future.
Let's do it.
Let's really do it.
Yeah!
Whoo!
Listen, two stars like you wasting your talents in a hole like this.
Secret admirer.
No, I'm serious.
I'm serious.
I got the hottest saloon in town.
I want you guys working for me.
In two weeks, you'll be famous.
I've been famous for 10 years.
Just give me the money.
I got the hippy, hippy shake.
Whoo!
I am the world's first yuppie poet.
The poem is entitled, The Bottom Line.
Money isn't everything, they say.
Okay, so what is sex?
It's better than sushi!
Did you ever make love to a pauper?
Pee, you!
I'd rather hump a camel!
Revolution?
It takes money to overthrow the government, you know.
That's deep.
Art?
The more it costs, the better it is.
And that's the bottom line!
Mark Holt!
You aren't poets!
I am the world's last barman poet.
Give us a kiss, you sexy beast!
I see America drinking the fabulous cocktails I make.
America's getting stinking on something I stir or shake.
The sex on the beach.
The schnapps made from peach.
The velvet hammer.
The Alabama slammer.
I make things with juice and froth.
The pink squirrel.
The three-toed sloth.
I make drinks so sweet and snazzy.
The iced tea.
The kamikaze.
The orgasm.
Hands up for merchandise.
The death spasm.
The Singapore sling, the ding-a-ling.
Ding-a-ling?
America, you're just devoted to every flavor I've got.
But if you want to get loaded, why don't you just order a shot?
I'd like to try the orgasm, please.
How many would you like?
Um, multiple.
Multiple?
Well, then, why don't we start with the turquoise blue?
Yeah!
Wow!
Whoo!
It's my soul, it's all I need.
It's my man, mother, it's me.
Prince of heaven, father, mother, give me love.
Oh, shoot!
Whoa!
Yeah!
Oh, baby!
You guys are amazing!
When things are shaking and the beat is weak, I can't even stay in my home.
I'm in love!
I'm all shook up!
Yeah!
Whoo!
Oh, yeah!
Oh, my God!
That was fantastic!
That was great!
You gotta let me take your picture.
What for?
When you're a big celebrity, I'll put you in Rolling Stone magazine.
My protege.
I discovered it.
That's great.
Can you move aside, though?
I can't fit you both in.
Excuse me.
That's great.
Oh!
I gotta go.
Mm-mm.
Mm-hmm.
Mm, Tuesday night?
Tuesday?
Yeah, I'm working.
So?
I'll sit at the end of the bar and wait until closing, isn't that what all bartenders' girlfriends do?
All right.
Bye.
Get in there.
You're gonna catch pneumonia.
Get out.
Get out of there.
Back off.
Get up, damn it.
Get up.
God, look at that clown.
Good night, sweet prince.
Looks like one of our customers.
That bum just cost me 50 bucks.
So what's this great idea I'm here to piss on?
Well, I have been doing some research into what it'll cost to set up Cocktails and Dreams.
Now, what I have found is, if we find the right location, do our own renovation, we can start it up for as little as 75,000 cash.
Ah, which the tooth fairy will deliver to our doorstep.
Hmm?
No, man.
Which we make... in Jamaica, man.
Oh, God, Brian.
Like that.
Hmm.
Jamaica, south of Soho.
Oh, yeah, man.
Very south of Soho.
The Caribbean Jamaica, man.
I was down there last month doing a shoot, and I met this bartender who makes $300 to $400 a day.
A day?
Whoo!
And he didn't have any of the talent of you guys.
Yeah, man.
Should have knocked.
Winter in the tropics, spring in New York.
Jet-set bartenders, eh?
and we can live for peanuts down there.
There are no taxes.
Cash off the books.
Two, maybe three seasons, and we are in business.
So you want to wait three years.
I've told you, New York is where the angels are.
Oh, come on, Doug.
This is...
This is a real opportunity.
Oh, yeah.
We'll have a fantastic time.
Will we?
Coral, huh?
Coral.
English.
Yes, sir.
Why is it you think these chicks are always named after inanimate objects?
There's nothing inanimate about Coral.
Hot mama, huh?
Yes!
Good shot.
Ten bucks behind the line?
Sure, shoot till you miss.
All right.
Where does Coral live?
76th Street.
She's got a brownstone.
She owns the whole fucking building.
You don't think she lives in that building all by herself, do you?
That's a bit lucky.
Scenic pictures?
Of guys?
Yeah.
Oh.
That's 30 bucks you owe me.
Jesus Christ, I know.
The man's on a roll, ladies and gentlemen.
So she's been saving herself for young Flanagan all these years.
Well, maybe she hides the pictures when she goes out.
Oh.
Have a look on her ring finger.
See if there's a white circle from her wedding band.
Man, are you paranoid.
Listen, it's the difference between...
A one-nighter in a meaningful relationship with an unattached millionaire.
Hey, I'm not thinking about her that way, okay?
This is more than just a one-night stand.
This lady's gonna do a number on you, mate.
I appreciate the concern.
Whoo!
That's 50 bucks you owe me.
50 bucks?
50 bucks.
Well, 50 bucks says that Coral's in the sack with some other guy before the week's out.
That's a bet.
Missed.
Hey.
Hi, how are you?
OK, how are you?
Keep it.
Quiet.
What do you have?
Screwdriver.
What?
I take it back.
You're not going to be famous.
Too bad you couldn't keep your mouth shut about our sex life.
It only gets better.
You made a move on Coral?
I had to get my money back.
You knew how I felt about her.
How could you feel anything for an assembly line hump that does the book on the first date?
I did you a favor.
I took her off your hand before she really twisted your mind.
You fucking son of a bitch.
Coughlin's law.
Never tell tales about a woman.
She'll hear you no matter how far away she is.
Come on!
Can't take the truth, eh?
Bullshit!
It was nothing but taking a cheap shot at me.
Where I come from, you don't do that to your friends.
Where you come from, they're still saluting the flag and making no penis.
No brawling in here.
And that goes for the help as well.
I don't work here anymore.
You want to cut me?
Come on!
You'll thank me for this one day.
The fuck I will.
Hey!
I want to take you to Bermuda, Bahama.
Come on, pretty mama.
Key Largo, Montego.
Baby, why don't we go?
Buddy.
Hey, Buddy.
The name is not Buddy.
Pal.
The brochure promised me a drink on the house, pal.
I'll take one of those orange things.
Excuse me.
Uh, my friend just passed out on the beach over there.
Do you have a phone anywhere?
No, no.
Excuse me.
She was, uh, drinking champagne in the sun.
Campaign.
Perfume going in, sewage coming out.
Is she gonna be all right?
Yeah, she's gonna be okay.
Could somebody go down to the conduit office and have them call an ambulance?
Yeah, sure.
Just in case.
Let's get her up.
The doctor will probably give her a shot of Ipecac.
I don't want anything more to drink.
Don't worry.
It'll make you feel better.
It'll help you throw up.
I don't want to throw up.
Oh, God.
I think I'm gonna throw up.
No, I'm all right.
I'm all right.
She can never make up her mind.
Hey, Brian, I got to hit the road tomorrow.
OK. Well, goodbye.
It has been an adventure.
I want to take care of you.
song I wrote.
You might want to sing it note for note.
Don't worry.
Be happy.
In every life we have some trouble.
When you worry, you make it double.
Don't worry.
Mark, I forgot about you.
No problem.
Welcome to my most humble, dishonorable establishment.
Well, thank you.
My worthless, useless services are at your disposal.
Um, I wanted to, uh, come by and thank you for helping out yesterday.
Sorry.
How's she doing?
She, uh, has a hangover.
Can I buy you a drink?
One of my rum specialties, perhaps?
I'll have a beer.
My kind of woman.
Hey, guys.
How you doing?
So it seems like happy hour all day around here.
Yes, happy hour.
That great American invention for spending quality time with spouse, souced.
A bartender with a mind for everything.
The bartender.
The highest evolution of the species.
Who's this New Yorker?
I used to work at a circus before I got this job.
Excuse me.
You wanna see a grown man cry like a baby?
Hey, bartender, you know how to make a red eye?
What, no tearful greeting?
Coughlin's law.
Never show surprise, never lose your cool.
Ah, my sons.
My rebellious sons.
Tell your old buddy how great he looks.
You look like a guy who dyes his hair and shaves with a Brillo pad.
A guy who gets an erection on his birthday if the wind is right.
Isn't this great?
Two years we haven't seen each other and we just flow into the old act.
Please, stop molesting the customers.
A daiquiri, if you will, bartender.
I taught this young man everything he knows.
I doubt that.
Don't you waste your loyalty on him.
He'll dump you after Valentine's Day.
Isn't that clever?
What the hell are you doing down here?
This lad is the best bartender south of 14th Street.
It's his downfall.
I don't see how being good at something can be your downfall.
Thank you.
If I grant you, it's not an easy concept to grasp.
Now, you take our hero here.
I haven't seen him for a while, and I've never been in this joint before, but I will bet my bile duck he's got some kind of success manual behind the bar.
Come on, Flanagan.
I know it's here.
Touche.
Voila.
You see, Flanagan's a believer.
Always will be.
He doesn't realize the doors are shut to people like us.
Well, maybe he wants to open them.
Then he has to steal the key, sweetheart.
Something Coughlin here has been unable to do.
Hey, I don't have to.
Not anymore.
I've had my miracle.
Oh, what?
Some alky remember you in his will?
Better.
I am in love.
There is my miracle.
Who, Pocahontas over there, waiting for everyone to notice her?
How dare you speak that way about my wife.
Your wife in your dreams.
For real.
We are here on our honeymoon.
Sweetheart.
Come hither.
You're married?
This is true love, young Flanagan.
True love with a kicker.
She's got millions.
Where were you?
I thought you drowned or something.
No such luck.
Brian Flanagan, Kerry Cogman.
The love of my life.
Hello.
Hi.
You see before you a changed man.
The love of a good woman has made me see the light.
While your lips are close to mine, we'll last forever.
Forever till the end of time.
Brian's cute.
How long have you known him?
About 10 hours.
My love is to the end of time.
Excuse me.
There you go.
I have never seen a club with such intense dance vibes.
Come on, let's decimate this dance floor.
I don't get the two of them.
Simple.
She's just a little rich chick whose family owns half of Manhattan.
Guess to piss them off, she decided to marry a bartender.
True love.
Let's dance?
Do you ever have the feeling that you might meet somebody?
You know, when you walk into some place or something.
Star-crossed lover syndrome?
No.
Because I had a premonition that I was going to meet somebody when I came down here.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
You still got time, you know.
Some woman must have really done a job on you.
Why does it always have to be a woman?
Well, it doesn't.
Your friend, what's his name, Doug, could have done it to you.
What's this?
Immune to Coughlin's fatal charms?
Give him a minute.
You'll love him.
All women do.
Well, I'm not like all women.
I'll give you that.
Of course, I'm not like all men, either.
Yes, you are an original.
Until you prove otherwise.
Uh-oh.
I better be careful not to lose my unique status.
So is this one night stand time?
Doesn't make you a bad person, you know.
Your parents own half of Manhattan?
No.
Well, then your virtue's quite safe with me.
For this evening anyway.
Tell myself I want no more of your record again.
The way I fought so hard and fast.
Thing I've never been.
In love, love, love.
Like I've never been.
Here I go again.
Heartaches take its toll.
You ain't got far to go.
If you travel soon, I'd be a pleasure cruise.
Heartaches take its toll.
You ain't got far to go.
If you travel soon, I'd be a pleasure cruise.
Smile.
So this is your profession.
More like my obsession.
So pay the rent?
Someday I will.
Right now, though, I'm, uh, waiting tables at Jerry's Deli.
Sure, I know the place.
Home of the famous Cement Danish.
Yeah, that's the one.
Yeah.
Hey!
Don't look.
It's not done.
This doesn't look like me.
It's the real you.
You know, you captured my innermost soul.
Oh, my God.
You should go on one of those.
Tomorrow?
You know, there's a guy who makes these.
One guy?
He must be exhausted.
Yes, he is.
But still, he gets up in the morning, and he kisses his wife, and he goes to his drink umbrella factory where he rips off 10 billion of these a year.
This guy's a millionaire.
How about the guy who makes these?
How about that guy?
I mentioned him.
The guy who makes these.
And those little wrappers are made by another guy?
What about these plastic things at the end of these laces?
He's probably got one of those weird names, too, like a Lugolbinder or something.
Lugolbinder, right.
We sit here, and we're surrounded by millionaires.
You rack your brains day and night to try to come up with a money-making scheme, and some guy corners the flugelbinder market.
Aw, poor baby.
He's frustrated.
You get a bar job to keep your days free for your real gig.
After work, you're so charged up, have a few drinks, you know, hey, it's party time.
Days get shorter and shorter, nights longer and longer, before you know it,
Your life is just one long night with a few comatose daylight hours.
Oh, God.
Stop feeling so sorry for yourself, Flanagan.
Hey, your flugelbinder is out there waiting to be discovered.
Waiting.
You think so?
I do.
I'm still here today.
I tried to pretend, but it was just a dream.
No, I just can't hide.
I had to swallow my pride.
And I had to run for the shadow of your love.
Run for the shadow of your love.
Run for the shelter of your love.
Ta-da!
No, I'm a man.
I don't like to cry.
But it's been pouring into your ear.
run for the shelter run for the shelter
I wish we could stay here forever.
Build a little hut over there on the beach.
I'd fish and pick coconut.
No, I'd do the fishing and coconut picking.
No.
Yes.
No, you would make thatch skirts to sell to the tourists.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
Thatch one, purl two?
Yeah.
We'd never go home.
Our kids would look really great in dreadnoughts, too.
Kids?
How you making out with that little blonde chippy?
How come I've always got the chippies and you're always with the princess?
Well, that's a question only you can answer.
This man's phenomenal.
Put him in a room full of women, and he goes to the poorest and the dumbest every single time.
The man's astounding.
His wife parades half naked on the beach, and he thinks she's just there for the sun.
My wife does not need other men.
You know what they say about sexual vanity in men over 40?
It's the first sign of senility.
Please try to keep your envy in check.
Ooh, envy.
He's my protege.
I taught him all I know.
Together with the token might get me on a subway.
You can only take a guy so far.
Then it's a question of biology.
Biology is destiny.
Ah, the old philosopher.
You see, there are two kinds of people in this world.
The workers and the hustlers.
The hustlers never work and the workers never hustle.
And you, my friend, are a worker.
God knows I've tried to beat that instinct out of him, but it's there ingrained in your immigrant blood.
Look how tasty your cocktails are.
Look how clean you keep your bar.
Why, man, you actually take pride in your work.
I do not.
Is he or isn't he a great bartender?
Oh, the best.
Yeah.
See, they love you.
Listen, Bozo, if you think I'm stuck in this gig... Face it, you're a career proletarian.
You've been standing in a puddle so long, you've got webbed feet.
Just because he gets lucky with a rich chick... Lucky, he says.
Why, you couldn't do it.
I've known this man for three years, and believe me, he's not a closer.
This place is crawling with moneyed females.
Case in point, rich and ripe and out of your league.
Out of my league?
Well, she just happened to be here checking me out the other night.
Maybe she had 15 minutes to kill.
You know what it'd take to make a score on a smart woman like that?
You'd have to get over on her, her managers, her lawyers, her trustees, her maid, and her tennis coach.
I've been training for this my whole life.
Well, 50 bucks.
Says you don't even make it over the bar.
Tell me.
That's a bet.
You guys are in on this.
Be cool, huh?
Yeah.
Mademoiselle.
Vodka on the rocks with a squeeze of lime.
Oh, no, no.
This is the tropics.
Please try a jus de more.
Pardon me?
A jus de more means juice of love.
It's made with fresh fruit right off the vine.
And trust me when I tell you that it is nothing short of spectacular.
Excuse me, do I have fuck me written on my forehead?
I can't see a thing without my contacts.
You're just full of confidence, aren't you?
Yeah.
Kind of makes you curious, don't it?
Mighty Casey has struck out.
Dad, don't.
The game's not over yet.
Wouldn't be any fun if they fell over with their legs in the air now, would it?
Bartender.
Excuse me.
Good night, Paul.
Good night.
Hey, Dulcie.
Where's Jordan?
She left on a flight back to New York late last night.
What'd you do to her, anyway?
Brian, are you there?
It's Bonnie.
Brian?
Come in.
Hi.
You found my secret hiding place.
The guys at the bar told me.
I've been thinking about you all day.
Yeah?
A plane ride home will cure that.
What I got, there ain't no cure for.
You can't send me away like this.
I don't know what'll happen to me if you do.
My business will go to hell.
I'll start writing bad checks.
We can't have that now, can we?
No.
You don't really want me to go away, do you?
Oh.
These drinks are going to be very tasty.
Into the market now, are we?
Mm-hmm.
What's my greatest talent?
Reading between the lines.
And that's what the market's all about.
Cheers.
I must admit, I never thought I'd see you set up like this.
Well, don't you worry.
I won't forget my close friends.
Kerry's old man has just backed me in the most luxurious joint Manhattan's ever seen.
We open in a couple of weeks.
You come back to New York with us and I'll make you head bartender.
Well, that sounds very nice.
But I've got plans of my own.
Like what?
Bonnie's hooking me up with her business.
I'll be heading back to New York with her.
Kept man, eh?
You think you made a breakthrough cutting that little blonde loose.
Meanwhile, your conscience is killing you.
If she hadn't left, you'd be back there begging.
You think so, eh?
Uh-huh.
And a bottle of Louis Trey's says you'll be working for me by St. Patrick's Day.
$500 bottle of brandy.
I'll have to take that bet.
On your feet!
Come on!
Whoo!
One, two, three, four!
Work those hips!
Come on, girls!
Yeah!
Whoo!
Feel it burn!
Yeah, that's back turning!
Morning, babe.
Whoo!
Listen, can you get me some carrot juice from the fridge?
Get some for yourself, too.
Whoo!
It's addictive!
Every fucking morning.
One, two... Yeah?
Well, no, just tell him not to make a move until he's seen our line, that's all.
And send Harvey down to Dallas right away.
You all?
Uh-huh.
Good, Tony.
Great.
You are beautiful.
Yeah.
OK, I'll be in the office in 15.
Ciao, Tony.
Tony.
Tony Scuduto, the sales manager?
Yup.
I thought he was in Mexico.
Just got back Friday.
Then I can go in and see him now?
Well, let it wait just a smidgen longer.
Remember, you're picking me up at 7 tonight.
Why don't you wear the gray pinstripe we bought you last week?
OK. Did you tell him about my marketing ideas?
Honey, I don't want him to think I'm shoving my boyfriend down their throat.
What difference does it make?
You're the boss.
These guys are top salesmen, babe.
I can't treat them like office boys.
Listen to me.
Look, you could wait six months.
You'd still be the youngest sales manager in the business.
Trust me, baby.
Hey, come on.
Get that heap out of the way.
How am I going to get out of here?
Hey, cool down, buddy.
Hey, you limo drivers are all alike.
You stand around with your finger up your ass.
Come on, move along.
Give us a break.
Art.
Hi.
Hello.
It's so good to see you.
Hello, darling.
God, it's been ages.
Hi.
You look fabulous in that coat.
Thanks.
That color is gorgeous on you.
Darling.
What a drag.
She said she was terribly sorry.
I was very.
Take my coat, will you?
Barney, let's get out of here.
Darling, I think you've had enough to drink.
Brian.
Barney, what are we playing, musical highballs here?
Come on, heel, boy, heel.
Come again?
Haven't got this one party broken yet, have you, Bonnie?
Brian, this is Robert Powell.
He's the sculptor.
Oh.
What do you do?
Interesting work.
Thank you.
Interesting.
It's very urban in orientation.
Robert, tell me.
Huh?
Did you get the cockroach to stand still long enough?
You're drunk.
You're ugly.
Uh, I'm OK. Robert?
Brian!
How could you do this?
Have a nice day.
Come on.
The suspense is killing me.
Well, at least you could apologize.
Apologize?
Yes.
Brian, we have to talk about this seriously.
Talk is overrated as a means of resolving disputes.
Blew my stuff out of your place this afternoon.
Left a can of Spam in the refrigerator.
I hope the brewer's yeast doesn't take it personally.
Bastard!
Oh, shit!
Oh, god, Brian, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Brian.
Listen, baby.
I've got some interviews set up for tomorrow.
Get it!
I am not a salesman.
I tried to sell out to you, but I couldn't close the deal.
Please.
I don't want to end it this way.
Jesus, everything ends badly.
Otherwise, it wouldn't end.
Believe me, Bonnie, you are going to wake up in the morning with a sigh of relief, because I'm not there.
Waitress, I'll be there in a second.
Excuse me.
Could you tell me what the specials are, please?
What are you doing here?
Bet you thought you'd never see me again.
Hoped is a better word.
Excuse me, waitress.
I'll be there in a minute.
Miss, we have theater tickets.
Look, you obviously are not here to eat, so I'd appreciate it if you'd leave.
Miss.
Waitress.
I'll be there in a minute.
I'm not leaving.
Your sexy little smile is not going to work this time.
That's it.
You're not leaving?
Not until you let me apologize.
Did you say you'd like to see the specials, sir?
I'd like to see the specials.
Excuse me.
Today's specials are meatloaf mozzarella, chicken a la king, and may I suggest some ketchup for your fries?
I'd think twice about ordering the specials if I were you, huh?
Spare change for my dry cleaning?
Sorry, payday's Friday.
You wouldn't treat a stray dog like this, would you?
A stray dog can be loyal.
All right, I'm a rat.
There's no hope for me.
But even I have a right to defend myself.
Least to explain.
Is this our waterfall?
No.
It's terrific.
Yeah, it's all right.
Name's Mooney, not Monet.
So, uh, why did you humiliate me like that in Jamaica?
How did I humiliate you?
Brian, I was there.
I saw you go off with that woman.
You're such an asshole.
It's not as bad as it seems.
You see, Doug landed a rich chick.
And that night he bet me that I couldn't do the same.
A rich chick?
So you'd go with a woman just because she had money?
No, it's not the money.
He bet me that I wasn't good enough to hustle her.
Hustle her?
And I was worth so little to you that you could just take some stupid juvenile bet?
No, you see, a guy lays down a dare, you gotta take it.
Brian, how do you think I felt seeing you go off with some woman after the time that we spent together?
Just hold on a second.
You were pushing me down there.
You were coming on too strong, too fast.
Oh, I was pushing you.
Well, you know, you happened to be there, too.
I thought that we had something going.
I didn't play any games with you.
I know.
I'm sorry.
I guess I just got spooked.
But now I know I can handle it.
Oh, you can handle it, huh?
So what if you got spooked again?
I won't.
I'll bet I can spook you.
No way.
I'm pregnant.
I'm spooked.
It's mine.
I was only asking.
Look, you're not going to be bothered or burdened, OK?
You can still go out and make a million.
Don't worry.
I'm not worried.
I mean, I am worried.
I don't want to talk about it anymore.
OK. Just go.
Why?
Because I want you to go, all right?
Just go.
You let me come up here just so you could kick me out, didn't you?
Mm-hmm.
No.
Get out!
I know you're upset, but if this is the way it's going to be, why did you even tell me about the baby?
Because I knew it would be the best way to get you out of my life.
Hey.
It's for cigarette change.
When you hand it to me, it's for change.
When you put it on the edge of the bar, it's a tip.
Hey, kid.
Hey, Uncle Pat.
How are you?
I got a problem.
You got time for a quick talk?
Well, make it fast.
I'm real busy here.
What's the matter?
I'm going to be a father.
That's it.
Bar's closed.
Finish up.
Come on.
Hit the road.
Let's go.
Eddie, finish up.
Everybody out of here.
You ought to know better than to come to a bartender for advice.
What am I going to do about this girl?
Nothing.
What do you mean, nothing?
She's not trying to shake you down.
She's not trying to make you marry her.
You don't care about her.
You can walk away from the whole thing.
What if I do care about her?
Then you got a problem.
Jordan, I just want to talk to you.
She's not hiding.
She's not home.
She's at her parents' place.
Go bang down near her door.
You wouldn't happen to know where that is, would you?
Sure, Park Avenue, corner 67.
Park Avenue?
Yeah, Park Avenue.
Listen, you get here when you say you will or you won't work in this building again.
Excuse me.
So you'll be here what time?
I don't mean to bother you.
What time did you say you'd be here?
Hello?
I'm sorry, what apartment are the Moonies in?
It's the penthouse.
Your name, please?
Brian Flanagan.
Are the Moonies expecting you?
No, not exactly.
All visitors have to be announced, Mr. Flanagan.
will you come in please?
may I take your coat sir?
there'll be someone with you in a moment.
I'm Richard Mooney.
I'm Jordan's father.
I'm Brian Flanagan.
I've come to see her.
Well, she's not here.
But come in.
Come in.
I'd like to talk to you.
Sit down.
Well, I certainly heard a lot about you in the last couple of days.
You know, I don't know what really happened between the two of you, but I must say, I think you've got a hell of a lot of nerve coming up here after what you did to my daughter.
I understand that.
And I realize that Jordan is very upset.
But if I could talk to her, make her see that I'm going to stick by her through this.
I hope you're not suggesting that you'll marry her.
I'm not sure what we're going to do.
We've got a lot to talk about.
The hell you do.
All right, look.
I know Jordan a lot better than you do, and I've never seen her as unhappy as she is at this moment.
She is just not very wise in the ways of the world.
And right now, what she needs around her are people she can trust.
She can trust me.
She doesn't want to see you.
She doesn't want to even talk to you.
Just wait here for one moment for me, will you please?
Good afternoon, Miss Mooney.
Hi.
Mr. Mooney, I think I'm just going to... Mr. Flanagan, here.
What the hell is this?
That's for you.
$10,000.
Is that all your daughter's worth?
OK. How much will it take?
I don't want your goddamn money.
You can't buy me out of Jordan's life.
You think I'm letting some bartender walk into my family and destroy my daughter's life?
That is her choice.
What the hell you say?
Her choice!
What is going on here?
Jordan, I came by here to talk to you.
Look, if you don't get out of here, Flanagan, I'm going to have you thrown out on the grass.
Jordan, I know the other night I didn't say the right things.
God knows I have not done the right things.
But I think there's a chance for us.
Brian, there is no us.
There are just too many things about us that don't work.
What about the baby?
I mean, a kid, our kid needs a father.
Not one that's not going to be around in a year.
Yeah, with your lifestyle, what kind of a father are you going to have?
Dad!
Jordan, I want a second chance.
No.
I deserve a second chance.
Brian, how am I ever going to know that you're being honest with me?
I mean, you can barely be honest with yourself.
Honest?
Were you so honest?
Why didn't you tell me you were the original rich chick?
Because you're so hung up on money, I was afraid that I'd never know how you really felt about me.
Me.
How you'd really feel about me.
This is your father's idea of how to get me out of your life.
This is how hung up on money I am.
And as for the way I feel about you, I guess you'll never know.
Hey, what about us?
Come on, let us in.
Henry, it's cold out here.
Henry, it never means I was free last night.
You look more like this couch.
Henry, I'm Doug's friend.
Look, Mr. Papa doesn't have any friends on a Saturday night.
Good evening, Henry.
Hey, hey.
Hey, hey, where's Doug Cobb?
He's over there.
Over there?
Hey, you!
You!
Doug!
Holy Doug!
Flanagan!
My best friend in the world.
My only friend.
Piss off, Henry.
It's okay.
It's great to see you, my only friend.
Sit down.
I don't know.
Looks like you've got a lot of friends here this evening.
Proctologist dream.
What?
Wall-to-wall assholes.
It's great to see you, Flanagan.
Yes, because you know I've come to pay off my bet.
Brian!
Gary!
What are you doing here?
I've come to beg and plead for a job.
It'd be great to get some talent behind the bar.
Well, let's go somewhere where we can appreciate this.
Come on.
Good time?
Get in there.
What are you doing out here?
Get in there and spend some money.
Keep me in the manner that I'm accustomed to.
Very good.
How are you?
Get in there and spend some money, you two.
What do you think of my rowing boat?
Jesus Christ!
Come aboard, you land lover.
Buckle of crystal.
Louis XIII, et voila.
Shall we let it breathe?
It hasn't breathed in 50 years.
It's dead.
Let's just drink it.
Health and friendship?
Life and love.
Douglas Coughlin, your ship has certainly come in.
My ship.
My ship is going down, and I'm going down with it.
How's that?
Oh, this is an illusion.
I'm on my ass.
I haven't got a pot to piss in.
Hmm.
A hundred grand a week.
Painful.
I should have read some of your sacred books, young Flanagan.
The only thing I know about saloons is how to pour whiskey and run my mouth off.
I knew nothing about insurance... or sales tax or the building code or labor costs or the power company or purchasing or linens.
Everyone with a hand stuck it in my pocket.
You must make enough to cover that.
if I'd stuck to what I know best, which is almost nothing.
Instead, I put all the cash into commodities and blew the fucking lot.
On the margin, buy, cover, buy, cover.
I wanted it fast.
See the headlines.
Douglas Coughlin.
from bartender to billionaire.
Hey, Doug, take it easy, huh?
Relax.
The luck is gone, the brain is shot, but the liquor we still got.
She knows nothing about this.
She thinks I'm a fucking hero.
My princess.
My dream.
Oh, baby.
Not again.
I want to go home.
Come here.
A toast, Flanagan, to the first and last person
Doug?
Doug.
Doug, wake up.
I want to go home.
You know you're the only person in the world Doug respects.
We were a good team once.
Walk me to my apartment.
I hate going to that place alone.
I better check on Doug.
Please.
I want to talk about Doug, about his problems.
Doug says you're incredible with women, a real lady killer.
Is that what he says?
What's your secret weapon?
Well, what you see is what you get.
What did you do that for?
I can't make it with my best friend's old lady.
Am I supposed to live with the same man day in and day out forever and have no one else in my life?
Yes.
It's called marriage.
You wanted this as much as I did.
That's why you're up here.
But you can't do it now, can you?
You're scared.
I don't know what the fuck I'm doing.
You're just scared.
Hey, Doug.
Help me!
Somebody help me!
Is there anything at all you can tell me about what happened tonight?
The Lord is my shepherd, and he shall not harm me.
My dearest Brian, a guy like me looks in the mirror.
He either grins or he starts to fade away.
And I haven't seen anything to grin about in a long time.
This may not be the most graceful exit, but I know when the bottle's empty.
About the only thing I'm really gonna miss is the conversations we had going.
At least I get the last word, even if I had to mail it in.
Coughlin's law.
Bury the dead, they stink up the joint.
As for the rest of Coughlin's laws, ignore them.
The guy was always full of shit.
But I guess you knew that already.
I know who you are, pal.
I've been instructed not to let you into the building.
If you just leave now.
Look, I just want to talk to her for a few minutes.
I don't want to cause any trouble.
Just send her a letter.
Get your hands off her.
Where's Jordan?
She's in there.
In there?
Yeah.
I mean, you can't go in there.
Open the door.
Jordan?
Jordan.
What?
Jordan, I have to talk to you.
What's going on?
Please, there's so many things, I don't know where to begin.
Doug is dead.
What?
He killed himself.
Oh, Brian.
He was my best friend, but he was too proud to let me help him.
He was too proud to show how he felt until it was too late.
I don't want to make that same mistake, Jordan.
He pushed right past me into the sitting room.
I thought I told you to keep that punk out of this house.
Sorry.
He kept behind me.
Jordan?
Jordan, are you in there?
I have saved money.
I've worked out a loan with my uncle for some more.
With hard work, I know I can turn it into something great.
Brian, I know you can't.
I know you can't.
But really, it doesn't really matter.
Listen.
Listen to me.
He was on the elevator before.
Give me that key.
I love you.
I want to marry you.
I've loved you from the first moment I saw you, Jordan.
Please.
Please, come with me.
Flanagan, get the hell out of my house.
Jordan, wake up.
Don't you see why he's come back here?
He's only come back for one reason, for the money.
That's not true.
I don't want to think from you.
You're not going to get anything, not one penny.
He's a loser.
I'm not a loser.
Please, Jordan, come with me.
Get him out of here, please.
Stay out of this.
This has nothing to do with you.
Please.
Throw this bum out of here.
Come on.
Don't regret it.
Just hold it.
No.
George, don't go.
OK. OK.
If you walk out of this house right now, just don't bother coming back.
Dad, I'm going.
I love him.
I'm going.
You're not going anywhere.
George.
George, stop her.
Get off of me.
Put your hands off her.
She's pregnant.
You asshole.
Dad.
It didn't have to be this way, you know.
You're on your own.
It's the only way I want it.
A toast to the bride and to my nephew.
All the happiness.
When will I be loved?
I've been turned down.
I've been pushed round.
When will I be loved?
You realize we're both completely insane?
Yes.
You're probably going to want to divorce me in three weeks.
Probably.
No, you'll want to divorce me.
You're going to be all fat and ugly.
Just as long as you don't get too fat.
I am going to be very fat, and you are going to love it.
Okay, a poem.
Well, this poem is entitled... Flanagan's Advice to His Unborn Child.
Now, if Jordan gives birth to a fine Irish son, there'll be cocktails and dreams for him one day to run.
A business that shall yield a financial windfall.
It better.
To be franchised in every suburban shopping mall.
A dynasty, founding a dynasty.
Now, if a daughter arrives to bless our clan,
I guess the shit will certainly hit the fan.
But this I shall promise to thee.
I'll never let her marry a guy like me.
But still, if our child's the naughtiest of girls or the wildest of young men, I swear I'll be the best dad I can and never ever get spooked again.
You bet I can still spook you.
No way.
Twins?
Twins!
Drinks are on the house!
Show's on!
Tart is open!
Here I go again.
Heartaches take you slow.
You ain't got far to go.
If you travel soon, I'd be a pleasure cruise.
Oh, I love you so.
I guess, I guess, I guess you know.
Took a bus, took a plane, took a railroad train just to get on back.
To find that little girl I love standing in the back.
We low, low, low, like they're in the back.
We low, low, low, on the railroad track.
Heartaches take it slow.
You ain't got far to go.
If you just do my dear pleasure cruise.
Oh, I love you so.
I guess, I guess, I guess you know.
Yes, I guess, I guess you know.
If there's any chance at all Somewhere down this road To be wild again
and it comes down to the question
Thank you.